## **Shewale Ajit Chandrakant**

Contact address

Contact: 9021247798

Email: ajitshewale3224@gmail.com

Taljai Parisar, Dhankawadi Pune 411043

### **Summary**

Java developer with 8.4 years of experience in designing, developing, testing, and implementing web applications, web Services and microservices.

I have handled all responsibilities, including requirement gathering, coding, debugging, and testing the application. I am responsible for the complete software development life cycle.

Technology expertise of around 6.4 years includes JAVA technology, and I have knowledge of MVC frameworks such as Spring MCV and Spring Boot, also has good knowledge of Oracle (PLSQL), jQuery, JavaScript, CSS, HTML. 2 years of expertise with mobile application development, WordPress, and PHP

#### **Employment History**

- 1. **Zensar technology** as Technical Lead (from Dec 2017 to Feb 2024)
  - Managed the entire software development process, from conception to deployment.
  - Built databases and table structures for web applications.
  - Providing technical guidance and support to the team, as well as mentoring and coaching team members on best practices.
- 2. **Neo-Soft technologies** as Software Developer (from March 2017 to Dec 2017)
  - Part of Front-end development team, Designing and Developing Hybrid mobile application.
- 3. **Hummingbird web solution** as Software Developer (from May 2016 to Nov 2016)
  - Developing the WordPress Plugins and also providing technical support.
- 4. Hyper-ions research lab Pvt. Ltd as Software Developer (Nov 2014 to Oct 2015)
  - Developing the Hybrid mobile application as well as web application

### **Technical Skills**

| Languages               | Core Java, Java 8, JavaScript                                   |
|-------------------------|---|
| Framework               | Spring MVC, Spring Boot, jQuery, AngularJS1                     |
| Database                | PostgreSQL  |
| <b>Deployment tools</b> | Jenkins, code console, Spinnaker, OpenShift, Udeploy & Urelease |
| Management Tools        | JIRA, Rally   |
| Domains                 | Pricing, Banking  |

### **Educational Qualification**

- M.Sc. (Computer science) in 2013 from Pune University with Higher Second Class
- ▶ B.Sc. (Computer science) in 2011 from Pune University with First Class

#### **Achievements**

- ➤ Win Hackathon competition Zensar Pune Event 2018.
- Winner of Zensar Team Customer Centricity Award for CMS 2019.

# **Professional Experience**

| Project          | Pricing & Quoting tool   |
|------------------|--|
| Summary          | CMS Pricing and Quoting Tool is a Cisco internal web tool that enables CMS product managers to update their product pricing consistently across portfolio, provides sales the capability to generate high level budgetary quotes and the customer-facing sales quotes based upon detailed configuration requirement, and helps deal governance team to evaluate and approve the deals based upon calculated cost and margin.   |
| Technologies     | Java, Spring MVC, jQuery, PLSQL, Git   |
| Responsibilities | <ul> <li>Responsible for development, design, analysis, integration, testing, UI design &amp; Backend design</li> <li>Involved in Architecture Designing of various modules.</li> <li>Involved in code deployment on Stage &amp; Production.</li> <li>Co-ordinated with the BA Team &amp; development team defining the scope of the Sprint and scope of release.</li> <li>Created Cron and Scheduled process.</li> <li>Provided support for the project – resolving ticket</li> <li>Providing technical guidance and support to the team, as well as mentoring and helping them for onboarding project.</li> <li>Reviewed the team members' code</li> </ul> |
| Project          | Jasper connects  |
| Summary          | It is one-stop-shop for Control Centre product information, sales and marketing materials, online training courses, knowledge base articles, support status and more.  |
| Technologies     | Java, Spring MVC, PLSQL & AngularJS1   |
| Responsibilities | <ul> <li>Understood the requirement from the BA team.</li> <li>Written the Cron job.</li> <li>Involved in code deployment on Stage &amp; Production</li> <li>Co-ordinating with backend team &amp; developing the API.</li> <li>Designing the application using CSS &amp; Bootstrap.</li> </ul>  |
| Project          | Kumar App  |
| Summary          | Interactive app which helps sales team at Kumar to showcase their product in efficient way & help them sales process. App includes information about Ongoing Projects, Completed, and residential Projects & Commercial projects. Users can visualize the projects by looking at 3D cut section, Amenities, Floor plans, layout, video, location.  App took all the data from brochures & made the selling process paperless.  |
|                  |  |
| Technologies     | Android  |

# Personal details:

Date of Birth: 3rd June 1991

**Gender:** Male

Marital Status: Single

**Hobbies:** Playing Cricket, watching movie

Place: Pune Signature: Shewale Ajit Chandrakant